# Joshua Rodriguez

New York, New York, United States



joshua32eb@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/joshua-rodriguez-48b8aa22b

# **Summary**

Dedicated engineer always seeking to expand his knowledge and grasp of the tech world. Been on the field for about two years now, working on various projects ranging from database engineering and visualization to a python-based web app which used JavaScript-based technologies on the front end such as socketlo to pass information between clients and various amazon's web services as the basic infrastructure for many back end systems, these include DynamoDB, Elastic beanstalk, Cognito, and the Botocore exceptions module for error handling.

### **Experience**



#### Full Stack Engineer (Javascript-based)

Self-Employed

Nov 2021 - Present (8 months +)

Full stack engineer with a good grasp on both spectrums of the job (frontend and backend) as both, individual components and as two conjoined entities who must constantly interact and work together in order to provide a cohesive and seamless experience for the user as fast and efficiently as possible. Although I have a good grasp on Vue and Angular as most devs should nowadays, I mostly excel in React which I heavily focus on (mostly because I enjoy the framework, JSX works really well with my workflow and having my html alongside my js helps me think a lot more). Coming from both OOP and MySQL engineering backgrounds, I easily got the hang of functional and class based components, applying either solution where It's necessary/most efficient prioritizing of course functional components, making good use of the many React hooks to expand the horizons of what I can do with my code.

Although given the fact that last paragraph was all about the front end, It is also important to emphasize my experience with the backend. Apart from the work I've done as a data engineer/flask-based API's which I go into detail in another section, I also work with JS-based technologies on the backend quite frequently (depending on the focus and needs of said api), when I work with web apps, primarily React, I tend to use NodeJS and Express, in order to keep the tech stack compact as to not branch out too much, making the acquisition of extra talent a lot easier and mantaining our workflow cohesive and consistant.

It is not currently up and running as I am reworking some parts and adding new content, however if you wish you can take a look the git of my own personal website.

https://github.com/Gohostieee/Gohooters



#### Lead Software Engineer

Self-Employed

Jan 2022 - Present (6 months +)

Currently (on my free time) spearheading the creation of a modern, MERN-stack website, specifically a network of chatrooms which are mostly but not necessarily created with the specific purpose of

discussing current world events. Particularly we seek to target a techy/geeky audience, mainly those interested in concepts such as crypto/nfts/web3 and the such since those communities are A: relatively untouched with very little competition in some markets, and B: extremely zealous about anything they can get their hands on if they believe it forwards whatever crypto-agenda they may have, helping bring their holdings "to the moon". The website will ofcourse be a CRUD type website saving and reading as little information as we can in the most compact manner, in such a way as to not impact the user experience and to make good use of our mongo DB and keep spending at a minimum, with react at the frontend in order to garner good SEO whilst keeping a dynamic website, and node.js on the back end to lessen as much of the load as we can on the frontend.

As of February 24th, 2022 this git hub page is not up to date, we are currently looking to rework and rethink some aspects of how we are going to approach the front end, specifically css-frameworks and the such. Nonetheless here is the link to this project.

https://github.com/Gohostieee/news-web-app



#### API Engineer

#### Autónomo

Jul 2021 - Present (1 year +)

Working on a python based, flask api, used to interfaced with an mysgl database, hosted on a gcp instance, said instance is using a data scraper I previously created, to gather data on dynamic websites such as CoinMarketCap, said scraper is hosted on a Linux based ec2 instance. The database as of right now has about two hundred thousand entries, and with further assessment and a reallocation of resources, this figure is looking to increase up to at least one million entries by the end of the month. and the api itself should be going public in the coming weeks.

Github added as the source, however that repository is outdated as I've decided to make it private. https://github.com/Gohostieee/Finance

### 📵 Software Instructor | Quality Assurance Engineer

#### CodeWizardsHQ

Jul 2021 - Jun 2022 (1 year)

Part-time job I got because I've always just enjoyed teaching, a couple of hours a week I go ahead and mentor people on coding and guide them to complete various projects assigned to them without actually doing it for them obviously, essentially just giving them the tools to carve out their own image, with the closest allegory to this in an actual IT environment being that of a software engineer creating the design document and instructing everyone on the direction they're going to take with the project. I also peer reviewed a lot of the code/material that was going to be used, making sure it upheld company standards.



#### Full Stack Engineer (Python-based)

#### Self Employed

Jun 2021 - Jan 2022 (8 months)

Now this is an incomplete terminal based chat application. I was making it in pure python using lowlevel socket technology, this project was quickly replaced by my Flask chat app also used socket based technology, this one however was higher level but I did get quite a ways into this project and got a good understanding of networking, with some documentation by my side I could easily pick this back up again.

https://github.com/Gohostieee/terminalChatApp

As I state at the start of my resume I worked on a Flask chat app that of course used python-AWS in order to handle most server functions equipped with key-based fernet encryption in order to store tokens and login auth information, It is also set up to be easily interchangeable with any other form of encryption such as a hash key.

This is the most professional of my projects as it is the most recent and it sports a clean, team-oriented, and organized coding format where everything is organized into their own respective modules, and all the functions are stored separately and called into the main py file making it possible to easily translate these functions into another project and just bundle them as a library and allowing the developers to move along the files with ease.

https://github.com/Gohostieee/FlaskChatApp

A project where I focused on classes in python and took a project where it was focused all around on these, just to get some good practice, it is a loan calculator in which the user is asked for various information about the said loan and it is then formatted into a class which is mold-able and dynamic with the ability to change already established characteristics such as the date and calculate its worth in for example ten years down the road.

https://github.com/Gohostieee/loanSQL



#### Data Engineer

#### Self Employed

Jan 2021 - Present (1 year 6 months +)

Created the first part of a two-part project in which I sought to create an easy-to-access database of block-chain stock data. The first part was essentially a web scraper created using a combination of selenium and bs4, the website used to gain the information was coinmarketcap which was a dynamically rendered website with various methods created to circumvent data mining, I got around this by creating a selenium instance and zooming out in order to render all of the content, and since the classes are constantly shifting names I made it so that it automatically looped through where the data I wanted was stored and manually stripped off the information with the help of bs4, which then was formatted into a clean array and sent into a MySql table.

https://github.com/Gohostieee/coinMarketCap-data-manipulation/blob/main/database%20scraping/extractData.py

The second part of the data scraping project, this one is much simpler as it is essentially made to take the previous data and visualize it using various data libraries such as mat plot lib in order to create a bot that would take in commands and spit out organized graphs and data in order to compare different stock's data, which led me to discover something quite interesting!

At the moment of writing this, I am not the most well-versed guy when it comes to block-chains and cryptocurrencies, I just have a basic idea of what they are and how they work, so color me surprised when I took a look at some data comparison and saw that most of the biggest crypto-currencies all follow a very similar path, IE: if ethereum goes up, bit is going up, if bit is going down, eth is going down, at least on a weekly-24h basis. With the only real variety being big spikes of activity.

https://github.com/Gohostieee/coinMarketCap-data-manipulation/tree/main/database %20implementation

# **Education**



# Pontificia Universidad Católica Madre y Maestra

Bachelor of Science - BS, Computer science

# **Skills**

Amazon EC2 • Google Cloud Platform (GCP) • Amazon Web Services (AWS) • Python • JavaScript • Firebase • Flask • Bases de datos • Node.js • React.js